<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book Reviews on Arsh Siddiqui</title>
    <link>https://arshsiddiqui.github.io/writing/bookreviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book Reviews on Arsh Siddiqui</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://arshsiddiqui.github.io/writing/bookreviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Tale of Two Cities</title>
      <link>https://arshsiddiqui.github.io/writing/bookreviews/ataleoftwocities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshsiddiqui.github.io/writing/bookreviews/ataleoftwocities/</guid>
      <description>A Tale of Two Cities#Charles Dickens#November 17, 2021
5/5
I bought this book on a whim about a year ago, but didn&amp;rsquo;t start reading it till not long ago. I was told by a good friend that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t all that it was chopped up to be, so I went in with little thought.
I will say that the book began kind of slowly, but I enjoyed it all the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Murder on the Orient Express</title>
      <link>https://arshsiddiqui.github.io/writing/bookreviews/murderontheorientexpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshsiddiqui.github.io/writing/bookreviews/murderontheorientexpress/</guid>
      <description>Murder on the Orient Express#Agatha Christie#November 27, 2021
5/5
The interesting thing about my reading schedule lately has been that I have been alternating between classic novels and Christie novels. I am a fairly slow reader so it&amp;rsquo;s always fun going from reading something like Don Quixote (which I greatly enjoyed but took me a good bit of months to read) to Christie&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;And Then There were None&amp;rdquo;, which I read in about two days and could not put down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poems of Rome</title>
      <link>https://arshsiddiqui.github.io/writing/bookreviews/poemsofrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshsiddiqui.github.io/writing/bookreviews/poemsofrome/</guid>
      <description>Poems of Rome#Karl Kirchwey (Editor)#December 26, 2021
3/5
This&amp;rsquo;ll be the first ever full book of poetry I&amp;rsquo;ve read, and the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve really considered the poetry I&amp;rsquo;m reading since high school English. Sure, I have read a fair bit of poetry since then, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t really taken the time to analyze it like I used to.
Overall, this book was enjoyable. There were certainly poems I enjoyed, and the book did introduce me to Rainer Maria Rilke&amp;rsquo;s work, which I will certainly have to read more in the future, but there were also poems I just read for the sake of completion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Romeo and Julliet</title>
      <link>https://arshsiddiqui.github.io/writing/bookreviews/romeoandjulliet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshsiddiqui.github.io/writing/bookreviews/romeoandjulliet/</guid>
      <description>Romeo and Julliet#William Shakespeare#February 19, 2022
4/5
Given the many varying reviews of this novel that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen here, I was curious to see what I&amp;rsquo;d think of it after having finished reading the story. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know a lot about the story beforehand (besides whatever is in the public consciousness), and it&amp;rsquo;d taken me long enough to get round to the book, so I dived right on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tell Them of Battles, Kings and Elephants</title>
      <link>https://arshsiddiqui.github.io/writing/bookreviews/tellthemofbattleskingsandelephants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshsiddiqui.github.io/writing/bookreviews/tellthemofbattleskingsandelephants/</guid>
      <description>Tell Them of Battles, Kings and Elephants#Mathias Énard#January 15, 2022
4/5
I really enjoyed this book. It was, most of the time, an incredibly calming book that I found much enjoyment out of, which was surprising for me because I found it incredibly randomly. I discovered this book, mostly through its book cover, which was designed by the fantastic Peter Mendelsund. I happened to find the blurb on the book really interesting, and wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to find much about it online, outside of some book reviews.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Count of Monte Cristo</title>
      <link>https://arshsiddiqui.github.io/writing/bookreviews/thecountofmontecristo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshsiddiqui.github.io/writing/bookreviews/thecountofmontecristo/</guid>
      <description>The Count of Monte Cristo#Alexandre Dumas#August 5, 2021
5/5
For a while now, I&amp;rsquo;ve been continuously hearing people rave about this book, describing it as thrilling and exciting. And that&amp;rsquo;s coming from people who aren&amp;rsquo;t even that into classical literature as some others may be. After finishing the book, I can certainly agree with that sentiment.
Without laying too much on the line, this book deals a lot with vengeance, and slow, critically aimed vengeance at that, which left me continuously wanting to see what would happen next.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shadow of the Wind</title>
      <link>https://arshsiddiqui.github.io/writing/bookreviews/theshadowofthewind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshsiddiqui.github.io/writing/bookreviews/theshadowofthewind/</guid>
      <description>The Shadow of the Wind#Carlos Ruiz Zafón#January 4, 2022
4/5
I found this book far easier to read than many of the previous books I&amp;rsquo;d finished. That does not necessarily make it any better, but it is something to be noted. Mostly that I have spent most of my time recently reading classics and mystery novels, so a historical fiction novel (which is interest-wise down my alley) would have likely been a different read to begin with.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
